# José Carlos de Oliveira Júnior

218-940-7621 | josecarlosdeoliveirajr@gmail.com | joseoliveirajr.github.io

# Introduction

MS student in Computer Science and research assistant at the University of Minnesota Duluth. Currently working with opinion, polarization, and consensus in social networks with formal models and subjective logic. Previously worked with web and mobile development with JavaScript and C#.

# **EDUCATION**

# University of Minnesota Duluth

Aug. 2021 - Current

Duluth, MN, USA

M.S. in Computer Science

- Advisor: Dr. Sophia Knight.
- Research project: Investigating the suitability of Subjective Logic to model the evolution of polarization in social networks.
- Fully funded as a research assistant.
- Coursework: Theory of Computation, Artificial Intelligence, Data Structures and Algorithms, Modeling with Dynamic Systems
- Coding experience: Python.

### Federal University of Minas Gerais

Aug. 2015 - Nov. 2020

Belo Horizonte, MG, BRA

B.S. in Computer Science

- Advisor: Dr. Mário S. Alvim.
- Final project: Formalization and verification of sorting algorithms using the Coq proof assistant.
- Coursework: Theory of Computation, Linear Optimization, Information Theory, Graph Theory, Data Science, Quantum Computing, Game Theory, Logic Programming.
- Coding experience: C, C++, Python, Java, SQL, Coq.
- As Undergraduate Research Assistant (Mar. 2018 Nov. 2020), worked with the Coq proof assistant for formalization and verification of software. Also worked with Subjective Logic aiming to improve a formal model for group polarization in social networks.

# EXPERIENCE

#### Full-Stack Developer

Mar. 2021 – July. 2021

Most Specialist Technologies

Belo Horizonte, MG, BRA

• I worked with Angular and C# on the landing page of MostQI, Most's document reading tool. In particular, I made updates and improvements to the document analysis API, a tool that builds a graph that connects documents based on their fields.

# Teaching Assistant

Jan. 2019 – Dec. 2019

Federal University of Minas Gerais

Belo Horizonte, MG, BRA

• Aided the Computer Programming instructor in evaluating student projects, and helped students with additional classes. The programming language used in the course was Python.

#### Web and Mobile Development Intern

Sep. 2017 – Feb. 2018

BeeStart

Belo Horizonte, MG, BRA

• Worked on web and mobile apps for new startups with Laravel, Firebase, and React Native.

## Web Development Intern

Mar. 2016 - Sep. 2017

Rockett

Belo Horizonte, MG, BRA

• Worked on a tool for creation of websites with Angular.JS.